Vinodh Kumar

📞+91 8939261620 | 🖂 vino1393@gmail.com | 🏶 www.vino1393.com | 🖸 vinomanick | in vinodh-kumar-manickam-0ab18382

"whatever it takes!"

SUMMARY_

Software professional with 6+ years of experience specializing in the EmberJs, NodeJS and SASS development. Analytical thinker who loves to solve the customer problems in a most efficient and elegant way. Interested in learning new technologies and tools in this constantly evolving tech world.

EmberJS developer with a 3 years of experience building high performing reusable components, performance optimization and unit testing. Awarded best performer for 3 years.

SKILLS_

Languages Javascript, Java, Ruby

Frameworks Ember.js, Angular, jQuery, Gatsby

Style SASS, Bootstrap 3/4, Material UI, Tailwind CSS

Databases MySql, PgSql, MongoDB

CMS OWCS 11.1.8 / Oracle Web Center Sites aka Fatwire, Drupal 7/8, WordPress

EDUCATION _

St.Peter's College of Engineering and Technology

Chennai

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING IN ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING, GPA: 8.2/10.0

Jun 2010 - May 2014

EXPERIENCE

ASSOCIATE

Freshworks Inc. Chennai

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER May 2018 - PRESENT

- Implemented Field service management(FSM) module
- · Developed major features in FSM event scheduling dashboard, map view for tickets with agents tracking
- · Implemented gateway service in NestJs entry point for external systems into freshdesk ecosystem
- · Contributed to test suite migration from Mocha to QUnit Wrote codemods and custom assertions
- Contributed to the modular monolith movement by moving common components and styles
- Improved unit test coverage by 5-10 percentage
- Improved CI/CD pipeline and made builds more stable

Chennai

July 2014 - May 2018

Cognizant Technology solutions

· Collaborated with clients to read, understand and translate business requirements into technical aspects

- Responsible for development and maintenance of all the product hierarchy pages and homepage
- · Added support for products from newly acquired Dako company(Entitlement, Localization, new product templates) in OWCS
- Provided Production and Warranty Phase/ Full Phase support to client
- Created a data migration tool to import the products from acquired companies with a easy to use user interface for easy migration
- · Customized various OOTB elements in the OWCS tools to suit the client's need

Honors & Awards _

- 2019 Most Valuable Performer, Freshworks Career Assessment Program
- 2018 Best Team, Freshworks Engineering Award
- 2018 **Champion**, Freshworks Career Assessment Program
- Best Performer, CTS Go Perform Program 2016
- 2016 Extra Mile Award, DEP Dynamo Monthly Awards
- 2016 Rising Star Award, DEP Dynamo Monthly Awards
- 2015 Best Performer, CTS Go Perform Program

ACHIEVEMENTS _____

2014	Served as Youth Red Cross volunteer
2013	First prize in the Sudoku & What Am I? event at E Week 2k13
2012	Second prize in the Cranium Krusherz quiz at Crypton'12
2012	Third prize in the Quiz at Insipro Eclesia'12